Now, the functionality of
our game is almost there.
We can pick up this power-up, and then after
a certain time, the power-up goes away.
And then when we hit the
enemy, they fly off into the distance.
But one of the small problems is that when
the player, when the power-up is set back
to false, we have no
way of knowing when they
picked it up and when
it's been turned off.
So we're going to add a
visual indicator to be able to tell
when we've picked it up and
then when the cooldowns done.
We're going to go down
to our project window,
down underneath the assets
folder, underneath course library.
If we go to power-up indicators and open
that, you can see there's a lot of different
options that we can use to be able to
see when we've picked up a power-up.
Now we're going to select one.
So I think in this case,
I like selection ring two.
So I'm just going to
drag it into my hierarchy.
Now I'm going to rename
this to power-up indicator.
I'm going to fix it scale a bit just
because it's a little bit too small.
You can't even see it inside of the player.
It looks pretty good, it's a little high so
we can actually, let's see if we can bring
it down just closer to the
ground, something like that, cool.
Now what we're going
to do is we're actually
going to, in our
inspector, underneath the
power-up indicator, you
can see this check box
next to the name and next to the blue
cube, right at the top of the inspector.
If we actually uncheck that, so it
actually sets that game object as inactive.
So when we turn it on, we
can see it when we turn it off.
It disappears, so
that's just kind of useful
whenever we have different objects
that we don't need to show right now.
In this case, like the
power-up indicator,
we only need to know when
we have the actual power-up.
So that's when we turn it on.
Now what we're going to do is in our player
controller script, we're actually going to
create a reference to
that power-up indicator.
We need to create a
public so we can drag it
into the editor game
object, power-up indicator,
and then before we
get too far, because I
make this mistake too
often, in Unity, if you
click on the player, just make sure to
drag the power-up indicator directly in.
So now we know that they're attached.
Now, in our code, since
we have that power-up
indicator, when we pick up the
power-up, we should know that it's on.
So if we type power-up indicator, and we
get its game object, so you can actually use
a method to set something
as active or inactive.
So since it was
inactive in our editor, in
Unity, we can just set this
to true, and it'll turn back on.
And then in our power-up countdown routine,
since this is where we turn has power-up to
false, we can set power-up indicator,
game object, and set this active false.
So this will turn it back off.
So we'll just make sure
that works really quick.
We go pick up the power-up.
You can see the indicator on the ground.
And then when has power-up
is false, and it turns off.
So one last thing we need to do, it looked
a little weird, because it wasn't actually
following the player,
it was just on the
ground, so we can make it even
cooler by having it follow the player.
So in our player controller script, if we
go to our update method, we can actually set
the position of the power-up
indicator to the player's position.
Now when we press
play, you can see when we
pick up the power-up that our
indicator turns on on our player.
So there is one problem,
so this will set the
position to be exactly
the same as our sphere.
So we actually just need
to offset it just a little bit.
So we'll just use a vector 3 for now.
And we don't want to
move it on the x, we do
want to bring it a bit lower on the y,
but then we keep it the same on the z.
And now in our game,
you press play, pick up
the power-up, you can
see that our indicator
is following us on the ground, hit that
enemy out of there, goes away, perfect.
So what you're going
to do is in our course
library, make sure you
go to power-up indicators,
drag one of the indicators
into the hierarchy,
make sure that you set
the power-up indicator
to inactive and just make sure
to rename it so it's easier to find.
In our player controller
script, we're going
to make a public game object
for the power-up indicator.
And then we can just
drag the power-up indicator
from our project
hierarchy to that variable,
make it so that in your
update method, the
power-up indicator actually follows
the player as they move around.
In on trigger-enter,
make sure to set the
power-up indicator to active
using the set-active method.
And then in the power-up countdown
routine, make sure to set active to false.
Now it's your turn.